hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist now continuing with the topic
on test automation obstacles let's look
at our next obstacle which is called the
popup
windows so it's a pretty easy obstacle
if you know how to uh solve this
particular problem uh what we need to do
is uh in order to complete this obstacle
we need to click on this button okay
which is called The Click me and what it
will do it will open another window or a
window popup uh and what we need to do
we need to close this particular window
to complete this obstacle
okay so let's go ahead and see how we
can uh solve this particular obstacle
and tosa
okay so uh going back to tosa and here
as usual we will go to our obstacles
folder and then we are going to scan
this particular
application now here I need to just uh
add this particular control which is the
click button now you will think that I
might need to also scan the particular
window which is opening up but it's not
the case Okay so these popup windows can
be handled using a standard automation
tbox module and uh it is part of this
Windows operations okay so when we add
this Windows operation module I will
show you how we can uh handle this
particular window or maybe close it um
using this standard module which is
already present in tosa so we don't need
to scan this particular window again
okay so I'm going to save this and I'm
going to close this I will just rename
the module
now okay and then uh we will create a
new test case
here
and then I am going to add the
respective module to this particular
test case Okay so the first step is
obviously to click on the button so
that's pretty simple uh we need to use
the click operation for that and after
this um let's rename this particular
test step to click
button okay and after this the window
will open and then we need to close that
particular popup window right and as as
I said we can use one of the standard
modules okay so we'll go to modules
standard modules and then under tbox
automation tools okay we have got the
basic window operations inside this
we'll be using the tbox window operation
okay so uh let's go here into the
obstacle and I'm going to add this
particular module
here now uh as you know uh this dbox
window operation has got lots of
different operations which you can
perform on the window right so you can
see you can minimize maximize close um
weight resize move to Center so all
types of operations can be performed on
a window- based uh popup or just a
window okay now the only thing which we
need to provide is the caption so that
it can find the right window on which it
can perform that particular operation
okay and that can be done so when we
click here it opens up this
window and here you can see this is
probably the window title right so tric
centus at tric centus
SLX all right so I cannot take the
starting part of uh this particular
title which is Tri centus because then
my other window has also got tricentis
right but what I can do is I can use
this um X username which is at tricenter
uh this would be unique and rest of it
can be handled using the regular
expression okay so that's what I'm going
to do here in the caption I'm going to
start with the regular expression and
then uh add try
sentus and again a regular expression
okay so this will be static at resent
but the remaining part can be dynamic uh
it could be anything uh it will still be
able to uh find this particular window
using this particular title okay now
coming to different operations as I said
we can perform different operations on
the window now we can directly go ahead
and close it but sometimes uh if the
window takes a little bit of time to
appear then your test case may fail
right because uh your TS automation will
not fit it will directly go and search
for the window and try to close it but
if it is not present then the test case
might fail so in these type of scenarios
it is best to have a weight uh so we can
use this weight on
open right so this operation what it
will do it will wait till this
particular uh window is open right and
then it is ready uh where we can perform
some action on it right so in the next
operation on the same test step uh we
can perform a next uh operation which is
the close window right so this will
basically close that particular window
okay so we are using two operations and
then we are passing on the caption here
in the tbox window operation okay I am
going to call this close
popup right and then uh we come here we
change the work state to completed and
finally we are ready to execute the test
case okay so let me close all this
okay and uh get it back to the initial
State and now I can go ahead and execute
this
right okay so as you can see uh it was
able to perform both the steps which is
clicking on the button and then closing
the window popup right using the two
operations and uh this completed the
obstacle right so this way you you can
handle your window popups you can
perform a lot of different operations
using the standard Windows module so
it's pretty easy if you know what to use
uh in in a specific
scenario that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video